<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ortexo Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ortexo Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 19:29:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems in STEM Empowerment</title>
      <link>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/problems-in-stem-empowerment-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 19:29:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/problems-in-stem-empowerment-article/</guid>
      <description>Author: Elizabeth Field
STEM empowerment, for the most part, is a wonderful movement. It is an encouraging and unconditionally supportive community pushing individuals to pursue their dreams, despite what the rest of the world seems to think. It has had a substantial impact on many of today’s youth, providing opportunities, establishing contacts, and teaching important skills that may not be obtained elsewhere. STEM empowerment provides a degree of equity within the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of Successful NPOs: A Recap</title>
      <link>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/secrets-of-successful-npos-a-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 19:29:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/secrets-of-successful-npos-a-recap/</guid>
      <description>Author: Katie Li
On July 19th, five successful founders of the NPO Core community highlighted their experiences growing a nonprofit from the ground up—Chinmayi Balusu of Simply Neuroscience, Shrey Gupta of Irvine Lights, Gabby Banaag of Helloo World, Arun Mommileti of United2Care, and Shivali Gulati of Girl Genius. In NPO Core’s online webinar, these founders shared their tips and insights on how to transform any idea into reality.
Coming up with a mission</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started in programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/how-to-get-started-in-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 19:29:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ortexo.com/posts/how-to-get-started-in-programming/</guid>
      <description>Looking at our own team here at Launch Tech LLC, our programming experience and learning methodology differ significantly. Some of us took online classes in our own free time, some of us built foundations through Roblox or similar gaming sites, and some of us took classes in school. However, no matter where you begin or where you end up, no matter if your desire to program is purely professional, purely passionate, or somewhere in the middle, learning to program will give you the same couple of things: an altered, more logical view of the world, confidence in yourself and your abilities, and a new, highly applicable skill that will help you just about anywhere you go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>